<resources>
    <string name="app_name">quizzer</string>
    <string name="quizzer">quizzer</string>
    <string name="QUIZZER">QUIZZER\n</string>
    <string name="sym">Living Organisms are formed by various types of organic and inorganic biomolecules. Organic molecules involve macro biomolecules such as amino acids and mono-sugars or macro-biomolecules (high molecular weight, large size and slightly soluble). While, inorganic compounds can be minerals, water etc and are always macromolecules (low molecular weight, small size, diffusible and readily soluble in water). Both types of biomolecules play a huge role in metabolism.\n\nRole Of Different Substances\nRole of Water: \nWater makes 70-90% of the cellular pool and 65% which is around two-thirds of the human body, formed by Hydrogen and Oxygen atoms in the ratio 2:1. 5% of water is in the combined form in a cell while 95% is found in the free state. Water supports in sustaining essential life processes and hence called the cradle of lip and life is next to impossible without water.\n\nRole of Oxygen: \nOxygen is utilized mainly in aerobic cell respiration of the nutrients in the mitochondria to form ATP molecules which are energy-rich and 5% of the available energy is released in the absence of oxygen.\n\nRole of common salt (Sodium chloride): \nSodium chloride performs a huge role in metabolic functions of the body in ionic form.\n\nRole of Carbohydrates: \nCarbohydrates are the organic compounds consisting of C, H and O in 1:2:1 ratio and commonly called saccharides. Carbohydrates are the major storage molecules and many organisms utilize carbohydrates as a major fuel in breaking these bonds and liberating energy.\n\nRole of Proteins: \nProteins are the polymeric compounds consisting of monomers (amino acids) by peptide bonds. Only 20 among 100 types of amino acids are of biological importance. Proteins perform a major role in the building structures in the living organisms. Similar to fat and carbohydrate, protein can be broken followed by the liberation of energy. Protein is normally used only as a substantial source of energy in starving situations.</string>
    <string name="ani">Animals are eukaryotic, multicellular, species belonging to the Kingdom Animalia. Every animal has its own unique characteristics. They obtain their energy either by feeding on plants or on other animals. There are millions of species which have been identified, few share similar characteristics while others differ drastically.\nClassification of Animal Kingdom\nAnimals are classified based on their characteristics. They are eminent from algae, plants, and fungus where rigid cell walls are absent. Some are also heterotrophic, in general, they digest their food within the internal chambers which again distinguish them from algae and plants. Another elite character of these species is that they are motile, except in certain life stages.\nProtozoa\nProtozoa are the different group of eukaryotic organisms which are unicellular having some similar characteristics of animals such as motility and predation. Protozoa take in food by the process of osmotrophy that is by engrossing the nutrients through the cell membranes or also they feed on phagocytosis, either by the process of engulfing the particles of the food with the help of pseudopodia.\n\nBryozoans\nBryozoans are normally acknowledged as moss animals.  They are filter feeders which sift food particles out of the water using a crown of tentacles lined with cilia and most of them dwell in humid waters, few in glacial waters and some in marine trenches. Most of them are colonial and one genre is solitary. Zooids are individuals in bryozoans and they are not completely independent species. All colonies have auto zooids, which are accountable for feeding and excretion.\n\nVertebrates\nVertebrates are the animals possessing backbones. Some include jawed vertebrates and jawless fish. For example sharks, ray fish, and bony fish.  A bony fish named clad also further falls into the class of amphibians, reptiles, mammals, and birds.  Extant vertebrates vary in size beginning from the frog species named Paedophryne amanuensis to the blue whale. Amphibians are species that live in the land and move to water for breeding. Reptiles are covered by scutes. Mammals are terrestrial, aquatic or aerial. Birds are covered with feathers and have streamlined avenues.\n\nOrgan Level of Organization: \nAnimal tissues comprising of similar capacity are classified into shaped organs. Every organ is definite for particular capacity. For example Platyhelminthes.\nTissue Level of Organization: \nAnimal cells displaying division of exercises among themselves.Cells performing the same function cooperate to form tissues.\nOrgan framework Level of Organization: \nThe organ framework level of organization are displayed in those organisms where organs define the shape of functional frameworks and each framework is with a distinct physiological capacity.\nCellular Level of Organization: \nThis organization consists of animals with cells which are formed as free cell lumps.</string>
</resources>